Name: Rory Marthew Claude Grignard

Summary

I have more than 10 years experience in frontend web development, user interface design and email marketing. I write clean, maintainable W3C compliant code that is cross browser compatible. I specialise in building responsive websites that load fast and are accessible and intuitive for the end user. I also have experience building, and maintaining CMS websites with dynamic content using SilverStripe and Shopify Liquid.

In my spare time I've started familiarising myself with React using Create React App, and am really enjoying building functional components with JSX.

I am an enthusiastic, self-motivated individual who enjoys problem-solving, and interacting with other people. I am able to work alone or collaborate as part of a team.

Keywords/Skillset

HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Javascript ES6, jQuery, Bootstrap (3, 4, 5), React, JSX, Yarn, NPM, Node, Photoshop, Illustrator, XD, Figma, SilverStripe, Shopify Liquid, Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager, MAMP, Git, Babel, GreenSock (2, 3).

Specialization Overview

Operating systems: iOS, Windows.

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Javascript ES6, JSON, JSX, jQuery.

Libraries: Bootstrap (3, 4, 5), React. Git clients: Tower, GitKraken. Package managers: Yarn, NPM. Repositories: Bitbucket, GitHub.

Design: Photoshop, Illustrator, XD, Figma. CMS: SilverStripe, Shopify, Wordpress.

Professional Experience

Position: Web Developer Date: 11/2019 – 06/2022

Company: 7DOTS

Role:

- Building web page templates and components with dynamic content using SilverStripe templating paired with semantic and accessible HTML5 markup.
- Responsive styling of web page templates and components using modular SCSS.
- Programming interactive website interfaces using Javascript ES6.
- Creating advanced website animations using GreenSock 3.
- Configuring CMS pages and components using SilverStripe and PHP classes.
- Cross browser and cross device testing.
- Analysing PageSpeed insights and web vitals.
- Liaising with project managers, providing clear, concise and timeous feedback through each step of any given project.
- Deployments to staging and production servers.
- Version control using git.

Position: Frontend Web Developer

Date: 08/2015 – 07/2019 Company: Mr Price Apparel

Role:

- Development and deployment of responsive website content.
- Mentoring of junior frontend developers within the team.
- Development and execution of email marketing campaigns.
- Updating the mrp fashion app content using JSON via Google Cloud Platform.
- Creating and scheduling of app push notifications.
- Website maintenance and testing.
- Creating JIRA reports for bug fixes.

Position: Frontend Web Developer and UI Designer

Date: 01/2015 – 07/2015 Company: iX Online Motoring

Role:

- Designing website prototypes in alignment with dealership CI to act as the dealership's online storefront.
- Development of mobile first dealership websites using HTML5, CSS3 and jQuery.
- Styling website modules (specials search, and new or used car search) using CSS.
- Collaborating with the backend software development team to spec new modules according to client feedback.

Position: User Interface Developer

Date: 07/2014 – 12/2014 Company: FirstView Media

Role:

- Building amazing online experiences for brands, agencies, and startups.
- Creating wireframes using XMind.
- Rapid development of responsive websites using Bootstrap 3.
- Project tracking using Resource Guru and ActiveCollab.
- Liaising with brand managers regarding client feedback.
- Planning and execution of effective digital strategies for maximum ROI for our clients.
- Planning projects with brand managers.
- Planning development details with fellow developers.
- Collaborating with web designers and copywriters.
- Uploading websites files using FileZilla.
- Thorough testing of websites functionality and content.
- · Actioning hotfixes and client feature requests.
- Emailer development using Dreamweaver.
- Scheduling of email campaigns using Campaign Monitor.

Position:Media CreativeDate:03/2013 - 06/2014Company:iX Online Motoring

Role:

- Development of emailers using Dreamweaver.
- Email marketing campaign execution.
- Design, development and deployment of marketing content on dealership websites.
- Design of marketing content for social media platforms.
- Social media account management using Hootsuite.
- Facebook Ad campaigns.

• Collaborating with and providing feedback to clients with regard to their social media and email campaigns.

Position: Front End Website Support

Date: 06/2011 - 04/2013Company: iX Online Motoring

Role:

- CMS and website front desk support.
- Updates to client websites using HTML and CSS.
- Website content design using Photoshop, Illustrator and Flash.
- Communicating with the backend software development team regarding client feature requests and bug fixes.
- Creating tasks for the software development team, so that bug fixes and enhancements can be tracked.
- Uploading of dealership vehicle stock via FTP, XML and web services.

Position: Graphic Designer

Date: 02/2007 – 12/2008

Company: LS Branding

Role:

- Corporate identity design including logos, letterheads, flyers, and business cards.
- Textile print design for workwear and corporate marketing campaigns.
- Signage design and installation of vehicle decals and fixed signage using a variety of materials, including, vinyl, aluminium, perspex, correx and chromadek.

Education

Qualification: Interactive Media Certificate - SAQA Level 5

Dates: 01/2009 – 12/2010

Institution: Boston Multimedia Umhlanga

Subjects:

- Website Development HTML, CSS
- Programming Visual Basic .NET
- Graphic Design Photoshop, Illustrator
- Project management Microsoft Project
- Animation Flash
- Sound editing Audacity

Qualification: Matric Year: 2005

School: South City Christian College

Subjects taken:

- Art
- Business Economics
- Geography
- Biology
- English 1st language
- Afrikaans 2nd language

Interests and hobbies

Technology - Gaming, cyber security, smartphones, computers. Music - playing guitar, music appreciation.

Art - digital illustrations, drawing, legal graffiti.

Sport - skateboarding, surfing, snorkeling, fishing.

Thank you for taking the time to read my CV. References are available upon request.